Guide to the Graduate Liberal Studies Records, 1982-2019 UA.24.02.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Graduate Liberal Studies Records
1982-2019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Graduate Liberal Studies
UA.24.02.0001
3.0 Linear Feet
The Duke Graduate Liberal Studies program was founded in 1984, under director Bonnie E. Erickson. The program grants a Master of Arts in Liberal studies (MALS) and is sometimes referred to as the MALS program. The materials include programs, curriculum development, faculty folders, photographs, slides, and correspondence.
Biographical / Historical
The Duke Graduate Liberal Studies program was founded in 1984, under director Bonnie E. Erickson. Additional previous directors include Diane Sasson and Donna Zapf. The program grants a Master of Arts in Liberal studies (MALS) and is sometimes referred to as the MALS program.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Graduate Liberal Studies Records were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in 2019.
Collection Overview
Contains records from Graduate Liberal Studies program, including records of previous director Diane Sasson and outgoing director Donna Zapf. Some records were left in GLS by Craufurd Goodwin. The materials include programs, curriculum development, faculty folders, photographs, slides, and correspondence.
- Accession UA2019.0038, 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
  Materials have not been processed and must be screened for restricted contents before use.
  - Luttrell, Wendy (Box 1)
    These materials need additional screening for restricted content before use.
  - Looney, Jacqueline (Box 1)
  - Lerner, Warren (Box 1)
  - Wood, Peter (Box 1)
  - Lange, Peter (Box 1)
  - Willis, Susan (Box 1)
  - Koonz, Claudia (Box 1)
  - Wacker, Grant (Box 1)
  - Vogel, Steven (Box 1)
  - Klopfer, Peter (Box 1)
  - Keysarr, Alexander (Box 1)
  - Holley, Bill (Box 1)
  - Hauerwas, Stanley (Box 1)
  - Searles, Richard (Box 1)
  - Rolleston, James L. (Box 1)
  - Roland, Alex (Box 1)
  - Gavins, Ray (Box 1)
  - Rasmussen, Ann Marie (Box 1)
  - Quinn, Naomi (Box 1)
  - French, John (Box 1)
  - Price, Reynolds (Box 1)
  - Parker, Grant (Box 1)
  - DeNeef, Leigh (Box 1)
  - O'Barr, Jean (Box 1)
  - Clum, John M. (Box 1)
  - Clay, Diskin (Box 1)
  - Christensen, Norman L. (Box 1)
  - McIssac, Peter (Box 1)
  - Cartmill, Matt (Box 1)
  - Nathans, Sydney (Box 1)
  - Bruzelius, Caroline (Box 1)
  - Bland, Kalman (Box 1)
  - Master of Arts in Liberal Studies Course Descriptions, 1984-2002 (Box 1)
  - Counseling Services (Box 1)
  - Writing Programs and Workshops (Box 1)
  - Policies/Procedures/Personnel Documentation (Box 1)
  - 15th Anniversary (Box 1)
  - Marketing: Newspaper Clippings (Box 1)
  - Bloomsbury Project, 2008-2009; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd (Box 1)
  - Director's Correspondence, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Publications (Box 1)
  - Course Offerings, 1994, 2000-2003 (Box 2)
  - Hooding Cermony Programs, 2011-2017 (Box 2)
  - Ceremony, Anniversary and Event Programs (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 1999-2000; 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 2001-2002; 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
  - Annual Report, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Gopens (Box 2)
  - Kent Wicker, Writing Programs (Box 2)
  - Writing Program Workshop, Spring 1993 (Box 2)
  - Duke Daycare (Box 2)
  - Disabled Students (Box 2)
  - Public Safety (Box 2)
  - Office of Research Support (Box 2)
  - GPSC Support Services (Box 2)
  - Graduate Career Services (Box 2)
  - Housing Support Services (Box 2)
  - Social and Cultural Events (Box 2)
  - Health Policy Certificate (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association Committee-University Committee (Box 2)
  - Adult Degree Proposal (Box 2)
  - Summer Language Institute (Box 2)
  - Committee on Education Non-Traditional Students, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Committee Correspondence to Members (Box 2)
  - Board of Trustees: Academic Affairs (Box 2)
    Board of Trustees materials restricted for 50 years.
  - Continuous Registration (Box 2)
  - Admissions Policies (Box 2)
  - Kenan Ethics Program (Box 2)
  - Latin American Studies (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Programs-Special Courses (Box 2)
  - North American Studies (Box 2)
  - Slavic Studies (Box 2)
  - Study Abroad Programs (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies: Course Description/Syllabi (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies: Articles (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies: Current Items (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies: Bibliography (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies: Relationship with MALS (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies: Program Review (Box 2)
  - Warwick-Duke Papers (Box 3)
  - Duke/Warwick Workshop, 2009 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Americanism Symposium Nick Omerly, Marty Miller, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Clotfelter, Charles (Box 3)
  - Development- Isobel Craven Drill (Box 3)
  - Anlyan, William (Box 3)
  - Eldridge, Albert F. (Box 3)
  - Fleishmen, Joel (Box 3)
  - Friedl, Ernestine (Box 3)
  - Funderburk, M. Laney Jr. (Box 3)
  - Fuqua School of Business (Box 3)
  - Griffiths, Phillip (Box 3)
  - Pfeiffer, Kathy (Box 3)
  - John J. Piva Jr. (Box 3)
  - Ruderman, Judith (Box 3)
  - Siegel, Lewis (Box 3)
  - Strohbehn, John W. (Box 3)
  - Wealth, Poverty, Labor and Reform (Box 3)
  - Student Advisory Committee (Box 3)
  - Final Project Award (Box 3)
  - Final Project Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Graduation (Box 3)
  - Brochure Samples (Box 3)
  - Faculty Program (Box 3)
  - MALS Program Description: Duke (Box 3)
  - General Demographics (Box 3)
  - Self-Study, 2009 (Box 3)
  - Core Course Development (Box 3)
  - Course Ideas/Syllabi (Box 3)
  - Curriculum (Box 3)
  - Core Course Descriptions (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Registrar (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with Other Universities (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Other MALS Program (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with Congresspersons (Box 3)
  - Publicity (Box 3)
  - White, Richard A. (Box 3)
  - Continuation Proposal (Box 3)
  - Advisory Committee Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Advisory Committee Correspondence, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Pictures, 5 folders (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    photographs; slides; contact sheets
  - News Service-Duke University (Box 3)
  - Susan Schnsian (Box 3)
  - Diane Sasson (Box 3)
  - MALadjustment (Box 3)
- Accession UA2019.0042
  - Lottie Applewhite, 2 folders (Box 3)